<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: musings | Andrew Allen]]></title>
  <link href="http://aallen.net/blog/categories/musings/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://aallen.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-07T15:31:01-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://aallen.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Allen]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://aallen.net/blog/2013/03/03/hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-03T23:40:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://aallen.net/blog/2013/03/03/hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been meaning to set up a homepage for myself for some time now. I'm connected to the internet for most of my waking day and I make my living building things for the internet. It makes sense that I should have my own personal corner of it.</p>

<p>I have even started building a site for myself a few times in the past, but the main sticking point was the lack of the right platform. I've made Wordpress and Drupal sites for clients before, but a full-blown CMS seemed like to much overhead for what I really wanted, which was a mostly static site with a few areas that would be easy to update. Static HTML is refreshing to write; you don't have to play by the rules of a CMS with tens of thousands of lines of code at its core, but you also don't get any of the niceties that come with a mature platform.</p>

<p>This is where Octopress came in. I saw that it was built on Jekyll, a Ruby-based static site generator that I had used in the past and enjoyed. But Octopress is geared toward developers looking to set up a simple site and it has exactly that community behind it, full of github repos of themes and plugins to do exactly the sorts of things I was looking to do.</p>

<p>In the interest of getting something live before I get zoned in on another project, I'll leave the default theme in place for now while I work on my own custom one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
